Thomas Clarke

See my LinkedIn for more contact information – linkedin.com/in/tombclarke

Profile:

A degree in Computer Science is allowing me to explore my interests and fuel my passion for technology. I am task focused, have a positive attitude and an industrious work ethic, all of which are important for my degree and for the real world of work. I have worked in several different working environments, all of which are giving me new experiences to help build myself and prepare me for my future. I can adapt to new environments quickly and deal with problems effectively.

Qualifications:

Currently studying: University of Birmingham - BSc in Computer Science with a Year in Industry – September 2014 to July 2018

- 2nd Year Modules: Software Systems Components, Functional Programming (in Haskell), Professional Computing, Mathematical Techniques for Computer Science, Computational Vision, Modules of Computation, Team Project, Computer Systems and Architecture, C/C++ and Computer Security
- 1st Year Results Year average was 85%: Robotics (100%), Software Engineering (78%), Software Workshop Java (95%), Language and Logic (85%), Web Programming (88%), Foundations of Computer Science (with functional programming in OCaml) (82%), Artificial Intelligence (77%), Information Engineering (73%) and Multimedia Data (70%)

John Cleveland College - September 2010 to August 2014

- A Levels: Mathematics (A*), Physics (A), I.C.T. (A), AS History (C), Extended Project Qualification (A).
- GCSEs: 3 A*s, 6 As, 1 B and OCR Level 2 National Double Award in I.C.T. (Distinction).

Technical Skills:

- I can program in Java (experienced with the Eclipse IDE), C# (used in Unity), MATLAB, OCaml, Haskell, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (including jQuery and D3.js), PHP and SQL.
- Experience with designing and creating experimental data visualisations (see labs.majestic.com).
- Function programming experience.
- Programming robots using LeJOS and scoring 100% in this module.
- Good experience with version control system Git.
- Basic knowledge of Android Development and Visual Basic.

Work History:

- Web Developer, Hinckley Homeless group, September 2015, Voluntary: I created a new website for Hinckley Homeless Group to replace their original one using an agile approach to development.
- Software Developer, Majestic, July to September 2015: Using various web technologies and utilising D3.js, me and a team of 2 other developers are using the Majestic API to create data visualisations. The work can be seen at https://labs.majestic.com. I also represented Majestic at Leeds Hack 2015.
- Supervisor (promoted from sales assistant March 2015), Spar, October 2014 to present: Responsibilities include supervising sales assistants, opening, closing and operating the shop, handling money, and handling customer queries.

Thomas Clarke

See my LinkedIn for more contact information – linkedin.com/in/tombclarke

- Software Tester, Crane Electronics Ltd., Summer 2014: Exploring and testing a range of products to identify faults or problems and reporting them to the software engineer for revision. The main project was black box testing on an Android based device.
- Garden Centre Assistant, Woodlands Nursery & Garden Centre, October 2013 to January 2014: Responsibilities involved fast-paced customer service and till working.
- IT Department, Aston Martin, Warwick, July 2011: Responsibilities involved building new computers for the assembly line and installing them across the factory.

Achievements and Interests

- While at Majestic our best project used data on 50,000 Twitter accounts and displayed them
 in a sunburst diagram and I also worked on integrating Twitter into the project. The project
 was received excellently, and they used their trade mark 'Social Explorer' on it as well as
 pushing it out as a headline on their blog and newsletters.
- Attending various hackathons:
 - I represented Majestic at Leeds Hack 2015 (leedshack.org) as a sponsor, where I gave
 a short introductory presentation on Majestic, and worked with the attendees on
 using the Majestic API in their projects.
 - BrumHack 2.0 where our team created a fast-paced fighting game in Unity using C# and having to create extra C# programs to run within the game to gather information about various websites using Majestic's API.
- Taking part in UoB Games Development Society's Game Jams.
- Tutored in GCSE Computing and A-Level Mathematics.
- I have participated in extra circular activities including:
 - o an EPQ (Extended Project Qualification) based on creating an Android Application,
 - a Silver Crest Award based on Astronomy,
 - o a v50 volunteering award,
- Member of the Computer Science Society and Games Development Society.
- Bass guitar (achieved Merit at Grade 3).
- Socialising, live music, game design and travelling.

References:

- University of Birmingham Computer Science:
 - o Hamid Dehghani
 - o Tel: +44 (0)121 414 8728
 - o Email: H.Dehghani@cs.bham.ac.uk
- Majestic-12 Ltd:
 - Steve Pitchford
 - o Email: stevep@majesticseo.com